<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://aburns.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://aburns.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-09T15:08:48-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/</id><title>Andrew Burns</title><subtitle>The adventures of Andrew Burns</subtitle><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title>Alexa Skills and Vanity Metrics</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Alexa-Skills-And-Vanity-Metrics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alexa Skills and Vanity Metrics" /><published>2019-09-21T13:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T13:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Alexa-Skills-And-Vanity-Metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Alexa-Skills-And-Vanity-Metrics/">&lt;p&gt;The first project I made this semester was an Alexa Skill for UConn students. It allows users to get dining hall menus and bus time information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come soon …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for now:
Github Repo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/my_uconn_alexa&quot;&gt;https://github.com/drewburns/my_uconn_alexa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>The first project I made this semester was an Alexa Skill for UConn students. It allows users to get dining hall menus and bus time information.</summary></entry><entry><title>Bay Area HQs ranked by a summer intern</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Ranked-HQs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bay Area HQs ranked by a summer intern" /><published>2019-09-20T13:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T13:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Ranked-HQs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Ranked-HQs/">&lt;p&gt;Also can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@drewburnsbab/bay-area-hqs-ranked-by-a-summer-intern-f385cb5a5fe3&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Background:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer I flew across the country, from my small town in Connecticut to the Bay Area to work for a startup called &lt;a href=&quot;http://playbalto.com&quot;&gt;Balto&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout my journey, I was able to visit some famous companies’ headquarters. So naturally, I decided to rank them. Thanks for Julia from &lt;a href=&quot;https://kapwing.com&quot;&gt;Kapwing&lt;/a&gt; for the idea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2048/1*w9dx-z9AKEkhPMaQNsyBjQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;Me (right) at my not so fancy office this summer&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Me (right) at my not so fancy office this summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Some of these I visited on a previous trip to SF in March. Also these are meant to be fun and mostly comment on my brief trip to each office.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Uber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory on Uber: We were meeting a friend of our founders there for a tour, lunch, and a discussion on how to appeal to recruiters. We thought we were meeting at 1455 Market Street when instead we were supposed to meet at their other HQ, 455 Market Street. And it turns out they are pretty far apart. While this was mostly our fault, I’m going to dock points for Uber having confusing addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch at Uber: I heard from an anonymous source that Uber uses the same catering company that many big tech companies use. And that same source told me that Uber didn’t even pick just pick the lowest catering tier — they invented an even lower tier just for themselves. The food was akin to dining hall food which is disappointing for a company that just IPO’d. I expected better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Feel: The whole office and environment felt very corporate. The attire was much more formal than other offices and just didn’t really feel as fun and lively overall. Nothing really stood out, just looked like an average American open office space. &lt;strong&gt;Rating: 3/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2162/1*URGaBEYS051bOOVMRh-lsA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory on Twitter: Went there for an intern networking event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food: Now Twitter had some good food. They had all kinds of finger foods like little hamburger sliders, skewers, and other enticing options. They also had a refreshing assortment of fresh squeezed juices. I wasn’t able to eat some of the foods due to food allergies but I won’t dock them any points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Touch Screens and Monitors: All of them. Everywhere. They had all kinds of interfaces to see trending Tweets, view timelines, and see real time traffic around the world. Could definitely see myself wasting hours staring at those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Feel: Twitter HQ had a very “fun” feel to it. Although it was a bit over the top and came off a little corny. This could have just been because of the intern occasion though. There were plenty of little breakout rooms and a plethora of unique seating options. Something else to take note of was the lighting. It almost had a neon glow kind of vibe going on as the sun went down. &lt;strong&gt;Rating: 6/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Yahoo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*APJgdd3Lw7GE2xh3IAezNA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory on Yahoo: I visited as part of my school’s Silicon Valley spring break trip in March. We had a tour guided by a UConn alumni (Go Huskies!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food: We had already eaten lunch which was a shame because they had a massive outdoor cafeteria (the real one inside was being renovated). Instead we hit up the smoothie and snack bar which was pretty standard. I apologize for any Yahoo employees who had to wait behind 20 college students to get their daily smoothie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Feel: Yahoo was a campus. They had their own gym with personal trainers, a sports show recording studio, and even basketball courts outside. Every conference room had a fun name that was dictated by theme of each floor. While Yahoo is a shell of its former self, you can’t beat having your HQ right on the water. &lt;strong&gt;Rating: 7/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Nvidia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2560/0*lS8RfWcXxRW--gPE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory on Nvidia: We also visited here on the same spring break trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceship: Nvidia looks like a spaceship. Both inside and out. It looks like it could unfold into a transformer at any second. Everything is in the shape of triangles to pay tribute to how graphics are rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech: We got to go into their tour room where they show visitors all their latest graphic cards on full display. Stepping into that dark circular room felt like stepping into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Feel: Just being inside the building I felt that I was 50 years in the future. Everything was so sterile and precise, it felt almost non-humanoid. Oh, and they had a $80,000 coffee machine. &lt;strong&gt;Rating: Alien/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Twitch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*af5AbYxkIhngjD2N.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory on Twitch: I went to a speaker event hosted by Twitch about building remote teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games: The first thing I noticed when entering Twitch was the employees gaming. And not just by themselves. They seemed to be having a super intense Super Smash tournament. I wanted in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Feel: Twitch had the perfect amount of fun theming. And they stuck to the theme of gaming throughout the office. I enjoyed the dark lighting with a purple Twitch hue as the sun set. The attention to detail is what really makes them number one on this list. Even the bathroom signs were themed and the man/woman appeared to dance as you walked by it. &lt;strong&gt;Rating 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a cool office in the Bay Area, please invite me and I’ll come and rate it next time I’m out there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Also can be found on Medium</summary></entry><entry><title>Lessons learned from my first startup: Munchbunch</title><link href="http://aburns.me/MunchBunch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons learned from my first startup: Munchbunch" /><published>2019-01-21T12:47:20-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-21T12:47:20-05:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/MunchBunch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/MunchBunch/">&lt;p&gt;Well this isn’t the post I wanted to ever make about MunchBunch but here we are.
MunchBunch was a food ordering app that allowed users to order food with people around them to save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built the app in Swift and backend in Rails.
Acquired 200 users and 5 restaurants. Had zero idea what I was doing as a dumb sophomore so I failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a demo of the app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6zhYB3bA6YE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come eventually …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Well this isn’t the post I wanted to ever make about MunchBunch but here we are.
MunchBunch was a food ordering app that allowed users to order food with people around them to save money.</summary></entry><entry><title>ScoreKeepers</title><link href="http://aburns.me/ScoreKeepers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ScoreKeepers" /><published>2018-01-05T12:47:20-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T12:47:20-05:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/ScoreKeepers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/ScoreKeepers/">&lt;p&gt;I met Max a few months ago at ACM (programming club) and joined his group that was building out his idea for a new sports website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://sportssite.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;ScoreKeepers&lt;/a&gt;. After working with a small team on building it React, I talked to Max and he decided to let me build it myself in Rails. I then enlisted the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tjnoto&quot;&gt;Tim Noto &lt;/a&gt; to help with the backend. Max didn’t know a thing about programming but he learned quickly and was awesome in helping design the front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Scorekeepers is a sports platform where users can post articles, vote on article/teams/coaches/stadiums, and have debates with other fans on the site. The idea is a sports platform where users create the content and vote on what they think as fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Rails: I have made other sites in Rails but this was by far the biggest project I have done. The largest challenge in the building was creating a way for users to easily write and post articles. After hours of searching, we decided on using an open source WYSIWYG editor that we had to play around with a lot and integrate Clouindary image uploading. It ended up being super easy to use.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Teamwork: This is the first project I had to work on with other people which was hard to get used to. I had to actually document code and use a lot of git features I haven't used before like merging (a lot of merging and branches). Furthermore we all had to be on the same page about what was happening in each page and why we were making certain choices.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Design: This was very important because the goal was to get real sports fans and bloggers onto the site and posting. If the layout wasn't intuitive there are many other places to post their articles.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Marketing/Startup: I sent out hundreds of emails,DMs, etc. to sports bloggers across many websites to try to get people to post on the site. Hopefully they post!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q6le-NAgqiQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>I met Max a few months ago at ACM (programming club) and joined his group that was building out his idea for a new sports website called ScoreKeepers. After working with a small team on building it React, I talked to Max and he decided to let me build it myself in Rails. I then enlisted the help of Tim Noto  to help with the backend. Max didn’t know a thing about programming but he learned quickly and was awesome in helping design the front end.</summary></entry><entry><title>Wingman App</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Wingman-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wingman App" /><published>2017-09-30T13:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-30T13:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Wingman-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Wingman-App/">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years I have been teaching myself iOS development and the Swift language. I haven’t made a real large project for an app yet but I decided to make one when I thought of Wingman.
Wingman is an app where you can anonymously put two friends into a chat and see the first few messages they say to each other. You’re probably thinking, Andrew what’s the point of that? And there really isn’t a point. Its just something kind of dumb to screw around with. The only main purpose I thought of would be for middle schoolers to start drama by putting friends into chats with other girls or guys they like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built out the iOS app and did a beta on test flight. I also purchased a logo on Fiverr to round out the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Firebase: This is the first time I have used Firebase and it was a great experience. I utilized the phone auth to login users and then used the realtime database to store user data. Also I used Firebase functions to automate some tasks and get them off the client side.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Push Notification: I went through the process of push notifications, certificates, and that whole mess to finally just get those beautiful pushes. I hosted a quick web server that handled sending out the push notification with the certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Design: I had to make this app look nice because I wanted people to actually use it. I used a pretty minimal design but had to actually make nice looking buttons and flow that made sense for users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.
Shoutout to Max Janik and Tim Noto for helping me work on the idea and planning out how to position the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZW-iJZInpGo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Over the past few years I have been teaching myself iOS development and the Swift language. I haven’t made a real large project for an app yet but I decided to make one when I thought of Wingman.
Wingman is an app where you can anonymously put two friends into a chat and see the first few messages they say to each other. You’re probably thinking, Andrew what’s the point of that? And there really isn’t a point. Its just something kind of dumb to screw around with. The only main purpose I thought of would be for middle schoolers to start drama by putting friends into chats with other girls or guys they like.</summary></entry><entry><title>Stat Programming</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Stat-Programming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stat Programming" /><published>2017-01-14T12:47:20-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-14T12:47:20-05:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Stat-Programming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Stat-Programming/">&lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/SummerInternship&quot;&gt;GitHub Repo &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was my senior year of high school and I did a senior seminar on statistical programming.
I followed the curriculum of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/jhu-data-science&quot;&gt;Data Science Specialization by Johns Hopkins&lt;/a&gt; on Coursera. I spent most days going through course material in the form of lectures and short assignments. 
&lt;br /&gt;
I covered the following subjects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Data Scientist’s Toolbox&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;R Programming&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Getting and Cleaning Data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reproducible Research&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Regression Models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Final Project:
I used a database of real estate purchases in Mass to first try to assess the value of a home. I used different regression models that factored in numerous data points on each property including lot size, number of bedrooms, and town. Then I realized that one of the data points was the actual appraised value of the house by a realtor. Bad news: I wasted a lot of time trying to predict something that already existed. Good news: I was actually pretty close!
I then used this data to make a very interesting graph. I plotted the expected value of a house versus the actual amount sold for and found that the more you list over the appraised price, the less you will receive on average.
Take a look in the slides below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQf_RaSMmWzJ5zQGtOqbrFSn76omKDvqYqjexEHYOpTNZ93oTuDgSVEd1JH3k3tA5CfKz3wJ4cx7eY6/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=60000&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;569&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>This year was my senior year of high school and I did a senior seminar on statistical programming.
I followed the curriculum of Data Science Specialization by Johns Hopkins on Coursera. I spent most days going through course material in the form of lectures and short assignments. 

I covered the following subjects:

	The Data Scientist’s Toolbox
	R Programming
	Getting and Cleaning Data
	Exploratory Data Analysis
	Reproducible Research
	Regression Models</summary></entry><entry><title>Summer Internship</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Summer-Internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Internship" /><published>2016-08-31T13:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-31T13:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Summer-Internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Summer-Internship/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/SummerInternship&quot;&gt;GitHub Repo &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer I had the pleasure of having an internship at &lt;a href=&quot;https://learntoprogram.tv/&quot;&gt;Learn To Program &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know what to expect coming in to the internship and was a bit scared I would have nothing to offer them. Maybe I didn’t who knows …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first task was to write &lt;a href=&quot;http://learntoprogram.wpengine.com/ruby-language-beginners/&quot;&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; on an introduction to Ruby, the language which I know strongest. It took a couple of drafts but finally I presented something good enough to post on their blog. A few people have liked it on Facebook so I guess it can’t be too bad. During the process I got to know Ben, a college student working there for the summer. We made a good combo because he could write well and I knew programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next assignment was to write solutions to the labs on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://learntoprogram.tv/courses/html5-specialist-designation&quot;&gt;HTML5 Course &lt;/a&gt; on their site. This wasn’t too difficult but I had to make sure it was all correct. I would feel pretty bad if my answer was wrong and a student learned the wrong way from my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After small tasks in between, I was given a large project. I was tasked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/SummerInternship/tree/master/Learn%20To%20Program%20App&quot;&gt; creating an app that would allow access to one of their courses &lt;/a&gt;. The idea was to create an app that would load an JSON file of a course and fill in the text/videos/images using the same layout for each course. I used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and Phone Gap to make the app. After about three weeks of work, I finished the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I learned valuable lessons and skills of working as a team. It was an absolute pleasure to work for this company.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>GitHub Repo</summary></entry><entry><title>Bite App</title><link href="http://aburns.me/Bite-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bite App" /><published>2016-03-30T18:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2016-03-30T18:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/Bite-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/Bite-App/">&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/BiteApp&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this app as a joke originally. My precalc teacher is a pretty funny guy and has a lot of catch phrases he often says. I wanted to make an app for him that allowed him to have the phone say the phrases for him. So I made this app that allows the user to record sounds and also have the phone speak text.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I learned:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;How to use diction&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;How to record sounds&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;How to store sounds&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Making custom color scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I want to add:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Play sounds in slo-mo or fast&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Put filters over the voice&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Make it look better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of me writing about how the app works, here is a video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zgr7yqpUf_U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Here is the GitHub page</summary></entry><entry><title>ChemJokes App</title><link href="http://aburns.me/ChemJokes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ChemJokes App" /><published>2016-03-30T17:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2016-03-30T17:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/ChemJokes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/ChemJokes/">&lt;p&gt;Project 2 of the mega update: ChemJokes - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/ChemJokes&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I am taking chemistry this year and after hearing a million and a half chemistry jokes, I decided to make an app. The app sends you a daily chemistry joke. The jokes all come from a simple Rails &lt;a href=&quot;http://chemistryjokeapi.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; I created.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I learned:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Timers&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Notifications&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Layout Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some screenshots: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.gyazo.com/ab00bf29d3c7d1077b1784c2d91f2972.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.gyazo.com/7c52c6345b7419c7a5ca7bb1f66b348e.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Project 2 of the mega update: ChemJokes - GitHub 

I am taking chemistry this year and after hearing a million and a half chemistry jokes, I decided to make an app. The app sends you a daily chemistry joke. The jokes all come from a simple Rails API I created.

What I learned:

	Timers
	Notifications
	Layout Practice

Here are some screenshots:</summary></entry><entry><title>ToDo App</title><link href="http://aburns.me/ToDo-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ToDo App" /><published>2016-03-30T13:47:20-04:00</published><updated>2016-03-30T13:47:20-04:00</updated><id>http://aburns.me/ToDo-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://aburns.me/ToDo-App/">&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/drewburns/ToDoApp&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ToDo App was made a couple of months ago. It allows users to bookmark location and make tasks they need to complete at those locations.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I learned:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;How to use maps&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Core Data&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Date and Time in Swift&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Linking to other apps (Directions to stored locations with Apple Maps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of me writing about how the app works, here is a video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BxS16FTu4rloVXZFUUtFX2dyRW8/preview&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Burns</name><email>drewburnsbab@gmail.com</email></author><summary>Here is the GitHub page</summary></entry></feed>
